（美琴(みこと)）
ウフッ…
It's a penalty game, so you have to do whatever I say.
Who is it?!
Ever since the Daihaseisai, she's been acting like this...
（美琴）
フフッ… 罰ゲームなんだから―
Onee-sama!
何でも言うこと聞かなくちゃ
いけないんだから
Who is alluring you to do dream up such sweet, yet scary schemes?!
（黒子(くろこ)）
グワッ… 気になる！
大覇星(だいはせい)祭から この方
連日連夜 この調子
What should I have you do first?
お姉様ってば そんな甘美にして
蠱惑的(こわくてき)なお声で―
She's snuggling?
一体 どこの どいつに…
Onee-sama...
Who... Who is that fluffy pillow a placeholder for?!
まずは
何をしてもらおうかな　ウフッ…
（黒子）ほ… 頰ずり
（美琴）フフフフッ…
お姉様 その… その…
#17 Penalty Game
そのフカフカ枕は
一体 何の代用ですの？
エヘッ…
"Look, look!"
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
見て見て
"While MISAKA was hospitalized, everyone's clothes changed!" says MISAKA says MISAKA—
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
ミサカが入院してた間に
みんなの服装が変わってるって―
ミサカはミサカは… ウワッ！
Your clothes are too frilly.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
てめえの服装が涼しすぎんだ バカ
Don't go climbing on people who just got out of the hospital, you little brat.
つうか 退院早々 病み上がりの
人間の膝に乗っかって―
外見てんじゃねえ このクソガキ
"You're so mean! MISAKA just got out of the hospital, too!" says MISAKA says MISAKA—
ひどい！　病み上がりなのは
ミサカも同じなのにって…
All right, all right.
（芳川(よしかわ)）
はいは～い そこまで
That's enough.
Your lovers quarrel can wait until we get you to your new home.
心温まるケンカは 新しい滞在先に
着いてからにしてちょうだい
What do you mean by a "new home"?
…で
その滞在先ってのは どこなんだ？
It's one of my colleagues' homes.
さしあたっては 私の知り合いの所
You're dropping out of school, aren't you?
君 今の学校
辞めてしまうのでしょう？
I don't want to put up with that "Level 6" crap any longer.
レベル６なんつうもんに関わるのは
もう ごめんだからな
The person you'll be meeting with is in no
way affiliated with the research business.
これから引き合わせる人は
研究職の人間じゃない
I'm sure you'll find her to be a reliable friend.
きっと
君の味方になってくれると思う
フン！
So basically I have to deal with another one of these idiots.
また この手のバカが
１匹増えるってわけか
（上条(かみじょう)）
ハァ…
I really wish I could meet someone...
（上条）
出会いが欲しい
What the hell are you doing?!
にゃにすんれすか！
（土御門(つちみかど)）
にゃ～… カミやんが言うと
嫌みにしか聞こえねえんだよ
Well, when you say that, it sounds like you're just mocking us.
When you say things like that, girls always just pop into your life out of nowhere.
（青髪ﾋﾟｱｽ）
その言葉を引き金にして―
そこいら中から けったいな女子(おなご)が
出てきそうやもんな
That's right.
ああ そうや　カミやんなら
超電脳ロボット少女から―
You always seem to attract anyone, whether it be a super electronic robot girl or a spirit maiden of a fountain.
泉の精霊風お嬢さままで
何でも どうにかなってしまうんや
Anyway, take a look at this.
それはそうと ちょっと これ見てみ
"Shoulder Massaging Holder-kun"?
“肩もみホルダー君”？
Forget the design. My shoulders are stiff, man.
こう見えて僕 肩こり ひどいんや
I think this would be perfect.
これ 絶対 効くと思うねんけど
What do you think, Kami-yan?
（青髪ﾋﾟｱｽ）カミやん どう思う？
（土御門）フン！
It's a scam. And, even if you complain to them later...
どうせ こんな物(もん)
詐欺に決まってるぜよ
あとからクレームの電話かけ…
"...the better choice would have been to
have someone actually give you a massage!"
だから 肩こりは
義妹に もんでもらうのが―
いちばんだにゃ …て
お前のオチが透けて見えんねん！
I can totally tell where this is going!
Then how about finding a more effective
solution to fixing that stiff shoulder?
だったら 義妹に勝る肩こり療法
提示してみろや
I told you already! The "effective solution"
is the Shoulder Massaging Holder-kun!
それが この肩もみホルダー君やて
何度言うたら…
Well, if that's the case, then I know just the person.
つうか それなら適任者がいるぞ
Someone who always has stiff shoulders
and is all over those TV shopping goods.
しょっちゅう
肩こりに悩まされていて―
なおかつ
こういう通販グッズに目がないヤツ
So, in other words, world peace is about...
（吹寄(ふきよせ)）
つまり
世界の平和というのはね
Is Fukiyose here?!
（上条）
吹寄は いるか？
（吹寄）あっ…
（上条）一生のお願い！
This is the last thing I'll ever ask of you!
Let me fondle those!
もませて 吹寄！
（殴る音）
（土御門･青髪ﾋﾟｱｽ）ゴフッ！
All right, class. We're going to start chemistry next.
（小萌(こもえ)）
さ～て 皆さん 次は
先生の化学(ばけがく)の授業なのですよ
My classroom looks like one of those delinquent classrooms!
（小萌）
ほのぼのクラスが 一転して―
ルール無用の
不良バトル空間っぽくなってます！
This is for the sake of world peace.
（吹寄）世界の平和のためです
（姫神）つんつ～ん…
Starting today, you four will begin rehabilitation.
（ｶｴﾙ医者）
さて 今日から君たちも少しずつ
リハビリを始めるわけだが
Are you okay with Tokiwadai's winter uniform?
（ｶｴﾙ医者）
外出着は全員 常盤台(ときわだい)中学の―
冬服で良かったのかな？
"That won't be a problem," replies MISAKA-10032.
（御坂(みさか)10032）
問題ありません
…と 御坂10032号は返答します
The sizes are the same for all of you.
（ｶｴﾙ医者）
サイズも ４人一緒だが…
"There is no doubt that we are all exactly the
same," immediately replies MISAKA-13577.
（御坂13577）
計測するまでもなく全員一致です
…と 御坂13577号は即答します
"There is no chance of us having different sizes," adds MISAKA-10039.
（御坂10039）
サイズの違いなど
生じる余地はありません
…と 御坂10039号は補足します
"MI..."
（御坂19090）ミ…
（御坂妹たち）うん？
"MISAKA actually..."
（御坂19090）
ミサカは…
"Is something the matter, 19090?" asks MISAKA—
（御坂10032）
どうかしましたか？ 19090号
と ミサカは… うん？
"There's enough space for two fingers to
fit," reports MISAKA-10032 hurriedly.
（御坂10032）
指が２本も入るほど余裕があります
…と 御坂10032号は緊急報告します
"But all MISAKAs are supposed to be the same,"
says MISAKA-13577, expressing her shock.
（御坂13577）
全てのミサカは
同一であるはずなのに
…と 御坂13577号は
驚愕(きょうがく)をあらわにします
（御坂10039）
バスト そのほかは どうなのですか
…と 御坂10039号は―
"How about your bust size and other measurements?"
asks MISAKA-10039, suggesting a re-measurement.
精密検査を提案します
まあ 食事や運動によって
個体差は出るからね
Well, there are individual differences in eating and exercise.
"So is this what one might call 'going on a diet'?"
continues MISAKA-10032 with her interrogation.
（御坂10032）
つまり
ほかのミサカにナイショで―
世にいうダイエットなるものを
実行していたのですか？
…と 御坂10032号は追及を続けます
"Speaking of which, I have seen 19090 reading
a women's magazine," recalls MISAKA-13577.
（御坂13577）
そういえば 19090号が―
女性週刊誌を読みふけっていたのを
見かけたことがあります
…と 御坂13577号は
にわかに思い出します
"She has obtained information such as receiving good luck
（御坂10039）
その際 好きな男性から
もらった指輪を―
when putting an engagement ring on your left ring
finger," leaks MISAKA-10039, seeing the opportunity.
左手薬指に
はめれば勝ち組との情報を―
極秘に入手していました
…と 御坂10039号は
ここぞとばかりにリークします
"Ring... good luck..."
（御坂10032）
指輪 勝ち組…
"MI-MISAKA..."
（御坂19090）
ミ… ミサカは…
If you all did the same as 19090, you'd go through the same changes.
君たちも 19090号さんと
同じことをすれば―
同じ変化が得られるんじゃないかな
"MI-MISAKA will acknowledge her sense of
danger and run away..." says MISAKA says...
ミ… ミサカは 自身の
危機管理能力に従い 逃亡します
（御坂19090）
と ミサカは…
There you are! So you finally show yourself!
（美琴）
いたいた
いやがったわね あんた！
Oh... right.
これは まあ あれだ
Such misfortune.
不幸だ～…
Is that the first thing that comes to mind when you see my face?!
（美琴）
人の顔見るなり
その反応は何なのよ？
…で 何か
俺に用でもあんのか？　ビリビリ
So, what do you want, Shocker?
Do you really have the right to keep up that attitude?
今の あんたに そんな態度を
取る権利があるのかしら？
The penalty game!
（美琴）罰ゲームよ！
（上条）はぁ？
Were we still doing that?
それって まだ有効だったっけ？
Stop forgetting about it!
ひとりで勝手に
水に流してんじゃないわよ！
Anyway, you're going to do everything I say.
とにかく ホントに何でも
言うことを聞いてもらうんだから
Though, a commoner like you probably can't do much.
もっとも あんたみたいな
凡人にできることなんか―
たかが知れてるだろうけど
All I can say is do your best.
まあ その辺は
せいぜい頑張ってみたら？
あら？
Fine.
（上条）分かったよ
（美琴）あっ…
With pleasure!
よろしい！　ならば
何なりと申しつけるがよい！
What would you like first?!
Huh?
I must provide a suitable environment for milady.
（上条）
お嬢さまには まず快適な環境を
The insignificant commoner, Kamijou Touma,
（上条）
私 上条当麻(とうま)
何ぶん ふつつか者ゆえ
行き届かぬ点は 平にご容赦
hereby asks for your forgiveness in anything you find unsatisfactory!
Y-You idiot, don't fan my skirt from below!
ちょっと バカ！
スカートの下から
思いっきり あおぐな！
（黒子）お姉様…
（美琴）うん？
Onee-sama...
K-Kuroko?!
（美琴）
く… 黒子
な… なんという潔い直球服従姿勢
What a sincere posture of subservience!
This is no normal man.
この類人猿
ただ者ではありませんの
But!
しかし…
That is supposed to be my role!
本来 その役目は私のもの！
Stop it you idiots!
（美琴）
やめなさい バカども！
何の儀式だ？　これ
What kind of ritual is this?
What kind of a commander am I supposed to be?!
私は どこぞの教祖さまか！
She'll be taking care of you from now on.
（芳川）
彼女が これから あなたたちの
面倒を見てくれる人よ
What the heck?
何だ？　これは
Whoa, whoa. Already forgot about me?
（黄泉川(よみかわ)）
おいおい
もう私の顔 忘れちゃったじゃん？
Not you.
お前のことじゃねえ
俺が言ってんのは―
I'm talking about this inexplicable organism!
この説明不能な生き物のことだ！
せ… 説明不能とは何ですか？
What do you mean by that?!
Despite my looks, I'm a teacher, you know!
こう見えても 私は先生なんですよ
チッ…
細胞の老化現象を抑える研究は―
So they've already found a way to stop cellular aging...
もう完成してたってわけか
U-Um... that's not—
え… え～っと…
そうではなくてですね
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）かわいそうに
（小萌）えっ？
"How sad."
"She's probably going to continue with her experiments,"
きっと 実験ばかりで―
"leaving her with no free time," says MISAKA says MISAKA while trying to put a handkerchief to her eye.
このまま ず～っと
自由時間とかないんだって―
ミサカはミサカは そっと
ハンカチを目に当ててみたり
Listen to me!
（小萌）
先生の話を聞いてくださいです！
（黄泉川）
ワハハッ…
いやぁ つかみは完璧(かんぺき)じゃん
Man, you sure caught their attention.
Is that the only reason you brought me along?!
（小萌）
もう… つかみのために
連れてきたんですか？
Time to show you guys my apartment.
（黄泉川）
早速 君たちを
私のマンションに案内するじゃん
I'll go start up the car.
ちょっくら 車を回してくるから
いいのかよ？
You sure?
この俺を居候なんかさせてよ
Letting me of all people stay at your place?
No problem.
（黄泉川）
ノープロブレム
I have spare rooms, so there's—
部屋は余ってるし 何も…
That's not what I'm talking about.
そうじゃねえ
You do realize that giving me sanctuary...
俺をかくまうってのはな
学園都市の醜いクソ暗部を―
...is like facing everything that is dark about Academy City, right?
丸ごと相手にするようなもんなんだ
（黄泉川）だからじゃんよ
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）ああ？
That's precisely why.
Have you already forgotten my job?
私の職業を忘れたか？
I doubt there's anyone out there who'd publically
attack the home of an Antiskill member.
警備員(アンチスキル)の自宅をバカ正直に
襲撃する連中は少ないと思うけどね
You can't complain once you're dead.
死んでから文句言うんじゃねえぞ
No problem.
大丈夫だよん
Your name might even be put on their list!
お前の名前が 連中のリストに―
登録されることだって
あるかもしんねえ
Correcting those guys is what I do every day.
そいつらを更生させるのが
私らの仕事でね
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）クッ…
（黄泉川）…にしても良かったよ
But I'm relieved.
You seem a lot easier to save than what I imagined.
あんた 聞いてたより
ずっと助けるのが簡単そうだ
本気で言ってんのか？
Are you serious?
Just listen to yourself.
（黄泉川）
だって そうじゃんよ
Despite all you're saying, you're trying to
point out the risks your guardian is taking.
何だかんだ言いながら
家主のリスクをつぶそうとしてる
That means you're ready to protect us.
それって つまり 私たちを
守る気 満々なんでしょう？
This is why I hate dealing with these idiots.
だから この手のバカは
始末に負えねえんだ
He's late. What's he doing?
遅い！　あいつ 何やってのよ？
Be at Seventh Mist by one o'clock!
（美琴）
セブンスミストに きっかり１時
You know what'll happen if you're late!
１秒でも遅れたら
分かってるわね？
Good grief.
たく… ハァ…
これじゃ 私がバカみたいじゃない
It's kind of like I'm the idiot.
Today is somen too.
（上条）今日も そうめん
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）ヤダ！
No!
Why do we have to keep eating this?!
なんで ここのところ
ず～っと こればっかりなの？
What is this? Some sort of body-regulating magic in the form of food?
これって なに？
食という文化を応用した―
体内調整魔術の一種なの？
A lot of different people happened to give them to me!
たまたま
もらい物が重なったんだって！
Think about me! I have to keep giving variations
like salad style, pasta style, and udon style!
来る日も来る日も
サラダ風 パスタ風 うどん風と―
創意工夫に明け暮れる
こっちの身にもなりやがれ！
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
ムゥ…
Tsuchimikado Maika...
土御門舞夏…
I want to share this happiness with someone!
（舞夏）
この幸せを
誰かに お裾分けしたいのだ～！
This.
（舞夏）
これだよ これ
Maids aren't supposed to be too flashy.
メイドってのは
基本的に目立っちゃダメだからな
So I put some frills on my sleeves to add some individuality.
こうして
袖口や襟元に こだわって―
こっそり 個性を出してるんだぞ
I'm in a great mood right now, so you can
talk to me about any problems you're having.
今の私は
と～っても気分がいいから―
ちょっとしたお悩みくらいは
聞いてやってもよろしい～！
We want new recipies for somen!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ･上条）
そうめんの新しい食べ方が知りたい
I thought they were trying to reduce the salaries of government officials.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
公務員の給料ってのは
削減する方向じゃなかったのかよ？
This is an institution constructed for the
architectural engineering sector's experiments.
（黄泉川）
ここは建築工学の
実地試験を兼ねた施設だから―
So the university pays for some of the rent.
家賃のいくらかは
大学側が出してるじゃんよ
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
あっ そう
I see.
"Wow, amazing! There doesn't seem to be a speck of dust anywhere!"
すごい すごい！
チリひとつないかもって―
compliments MISAKA compliments MISAKA jumping on the couch.
ミサカはミサカは
ソファに寝転びながら褒めてみたり
They made you write a debriefing again, didn't they?
あなた また始末書 書かされたわね
ア… アハハッ… 何のことじゃん？
What might you be talking about?
When she has an issue, she tends to clean her room.
彼女は問題が起きると
部屋の整理整頓をする癖があるのよ
But since she doesn't plan ahead, she often loses her room keys...
後先考えずに やるから よく
部屋の鍵がなくなってたりするけど
I-Is that how you'd describe the person who's helping you find a job?
そ… それが次の仕事を
一緒に探してやってる―
恩人に対する言葉じゃんよ？
That means the kitchen's more or less the same, right?
…てことは 台所のほうも
相変わらずなんでしょう？
Whoa, Kikyou said the food I made was good!
（黄泉川）
おいおい
桔梗(ききょう)だって私が出した料理―
おいしそうに食ってたじゃんか
（芳川）
作り方さえ知らなければね
If you knew how to make it, that is.
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
うわぁ なんで炊飯器が
こんなに いっぱいあるのって―
"Wow, why are there so many rice cookers?!"
asks MISAKA asks MISAKA trying to count them.
ミサカはミサカは数を数えてみる
A rice cooker has a ton of different uses!
（黄泉川）
炊飯器は何でもできる万能の
逸品じゃん！
Still?
来ない
Misaka-san!
（初春(ういはる)）御坂さん
（美琴）うん？
Oh, Uiharu-san?
（美琴）
ああ 初春さん
I believe Shirai-san's was supposed to come pick up your baggage for you...
（初春）
あの… 白井(しらい)さんが―
荷物を受け取りに来ることに
なってたと思うんですけど
Oh, yeah...
She was busy making me do Judgment work—
私 白井さんに
風紀委員(ジャッジメント)の仕事を押しつけてき…
Err, I mean... she was working so hard so she said she couldn't make it.
いえ
仕事で手が離せなくなったんで―
So she asked me to come instead.
代わりに私が
Oh.
（美琴）
あっ そうなんだ？
Wow, Tokiwadai Middle really is amazing...
（初春）
さすがは常盤台中学
Huh?
It's amazing how you get to learn violin in school.
（初春）
授業でヴァイオリンなんて
すごいですよね
（美琴）
大げさね
なんなら ちょっと弾いてみる？
It's nothing to brag about.
Want to try playing it?
Like that.
（美琴）
そう… 鎖骨と顎で楽器を支える
Hold it between your chin and collarbone,
then lightly grasp the neck.
左手で そっとネックを持つ
Hold the bow at a right angle to the strings, then slowly pull.
弓は弦に対して直角に
そして ゆっくり…
See? Easy, right?
ねっ？　簡単でしょう
Misaka-san... I feel like I'm dreaming...
御坂さん
私 まるで夢を見てるみたいで…
（初春）あっ… ヒイッ！
（美琴）どうしたの？
What's wrong?
U-i-ha-ru!!
（黒子）
う～い～は～る！
まったく…
（美琴）アハハッ…
（上条）いやぁ ごめんごめん
Sorry about that!
You know, I'm the one who won the contest...
（美琴）
あのね 罰ゲームを賭けた戦いの
勝者は私なのよ！
So why am I the one who had to wait an hour for you?!
その私が どうして１時間も―
待たされなきゃならないのかしら？
（スパーク音）
W-Well... there's a good reason...
い… いや それには深い訳が…
あ… あれ？
確か 約束って１時だったよな
Wait, weren't we supposed to meet at one o'clock?
You came half an hour early?
お前 30分前から ここにいたのか？
Sorry about that...
そりゃ まあ 悪かったな
I-It's not like I was here exactly an hour ago or anything...
べ… 別に きっちり
１時間前から待ってたわけじゃ…
Misaka, you...
御坂 お前…
I mean, I—
だから その…
You want to make me eat this penalty game that badly?
そんなに 罰ゲームで
苦しむ俺を見たかったのか？
（美琴）えっ？
（上条）お前って実は―
You're sneakier than you look.
結構 陰険なんじゃ…
Guess I was right...
図星…
Don't try to gloss over how you lost!
（美琴）
あのとき負けたぶんざいで
盾ついてるんじゃないわよ！
The agreement was you'd do anything I say, right?
何でも言うこと聞くのよね？
Well, not anything, but as long as I'm able to...
な… 何でもと言われても
できる範囲が…
Anything I say, right?
聞･く･の･よ･ね？
Come with me!
（美琴）ついてきなさい
（上条）…て どこに？
Eh? Wh-Where?!
（美琴）
黙って ついてきなさいって
言ってんのよ！
Just come with me!
This is the first penalty game!
それが 最初の罰ゲーム！
There's more than one?!
（上条）
…て ひとつじゃねえのかよ？
"Handy antenna service"?
（上条）
“ハンディアンテナサービス”？
Oh, that thing where they turn your cell phone into a backup antenna relay?
ああ… 個人の携帯電話が
アンテナ基地代わりになるっていう
Right. Subscribers to this service form an additional network between each other.
そう 加入者同士で
ネットワークを構築できるの
それに ペア契約にしちゃえば
通話料も安くなるのよ
Also, if you sign up for the pair contract, you get a huge discount.
Pair contract?
ペア契約？
And right now, if we sign up for both the pair contract and the antenna service,
…で 今セットで契約すると
漏れなく―
they'll throw in a Lovely Mitten Gekota strap!
ラブリーミトンの
ゲコ太ストラップが もらえるの
What?
（上条）
へえ
So, come sign up with me.
（美琴）
というわけで 一緒に加入しなさい
ハァ… 要はストラップ目当てかよ
So you just want this strap?
Don't you already have a ton of frog—
つうか カエルなら
もう持ってんじゃ… あっ…
We're signing up!
（美琴）加入するの！
（上条）アア…
But aren't pair contracts aimed at couples?
でもさ ペア契約って そもそも―
恋人同士とかで
かわすもんなんじゃねえの？
I-Idiot! What kind of a joke is that?
バ… バカ！　なに飛躍してんのよ
You d-don't have to be a couple to sign up for it!
男女限定っていったって 別に―
こ… 恋人じゃなきゃいけないって
わけじゃないでしょう
You could also be spouses, for example!
例えば 夫婦とかでもいいわけだし
Hello? That's way beyond a couple, Misaka-san.
もしもし 恋人より
重たくなってますよ 御坂さん
えっ？
ば… ば… 罰ゲームなんだから―
Th-This is a penalty game, so shut up and just do it!
文句言わずに ついてきなさいよ！
To finish off the paperwork I just need your signatures and a photo.
（店員）
あと 書類の作成にあたって
写真が必要なんですが
A proof of ID photo?
（美琴）証明写真ですか？
（店員）いいえ
No, we just need a two-shot picture to show you're a couple.
お２人が
ペアだと分かるものがあれば…
ツーショットで写っていれば
携帯の写真などでも…
T-Two-shot?!
ツーショット？
What should we do? Just take one with my cellphone camera?
（上条）
どうする？　とりあえず
携帯のカメラで済ますか？
（美琴）
そ… そうね
I guess...
All right, here we go.
（上条）
じゃ 撮るぞ
一応 確認するけどさ
Just so you know, this was your idea.
これって
お前から言いだしたことだよな
わ… 分かってるわよ
I know!
ンンッ… 待ってなさい ゲコ太！
Wait for me, Gekota!
Okay, I'm taking it...
（上条）と… 撮るぞ
（美琴）ＯＫ　いつでも来やがれ！
Okay! Bring it!
Your face looks kind of stiff, Misaka...
（上条）
なんか 顔が引きつってんぞ 御坂
Why are you deliberately looking away?
（美琴）
なんで あんたは
目を反らしてんのよ？
We don't look like a pair here.
これはペアではないと思う
I guess we should take another one?
も… もう１回 撮ってみましょうか
Why does your face still look so stiff, Misaka?!
（上条）
だから なんで
表情が固まってんだよ？　御坂！
Why are you shifting your body away from me?!
あんたは どうして
私から重心 遠ざけるわけ？
Okay, for a two-shot, we just need to look like a couple, right?
とにかくツーショットってのは―
恋人っぽい感じで
撮りゃいいんだろう
（上条）ほら こうしてやる！
（美琴）ウワッ！
Let's do this then.
Sorry, Misaka!
（上条）
笑え 御坂
要は書類のための写真だろう
This is just for the paperwork!
We both know what it's really for, so there's no problem!
割り切っちまえば
問題ねえよ こんなの
Y-Yeah... You're right...
えっ？　ええ まあ そうよね
This isn't for real or anything...
（美琴）
別に
それっぽく写真を撮るだけじゃない
We're just taking a picture!
そうそう 写真を撮るだけ
Here goes!
（上条）撮るぞ
（美琴）イエ～ス！
Yes!
（蹴る音）
（上条）ウワッ！
Goodness. I knew that trusting that newbie slave to that work was a mistake.
（黒子）
…たく 新参者の奴隷と思って―
甘く見ていたのが間違いでしたの
You also seem to be taking things too lightly, Onee-sama.
お姉様も さっきから
あちこちで大盤振る舞いを
D-Don't get the wrong idea!
か… 勘違いしてんじゃないわよ
I just wanted the Gekota strap, so we
were taking a picture for the pair contract—
私は ただ
ゲコ太ストラップが欲しくて―
ペア契約のための写真を…
（黒子）
ンガ～ッ！
Then why didn't you just ask me for help instead
of lowering yourself to this brute's level?!
だったら
こんな男に頭を下げずとも―
私と お姉様がペアになれば
何の問題もありませんのに
Come on, let's take one then.
Wait, Kuroko!
さあ 撮りますわよ
バシバシいきますわよ
Let's create some memories that'll last a lifetime!
ここらで 一生の思い出―
Where are we going?!
作っちゃいますわよ
（美琴）どこ行くのよ？　黒子！
If you're okay with that, can I go home then?
それでＯＫなら
俺 もう帰っちゃってもいい？
（美琴）
男女のペアじゃなきゃ
ダメだっつってんでしょうが！
It has to be a boy-girl pair!!
（スパーク音）
（上条）ウワッ…
And coming back to act alongside her in the movie will be Hitotsui Hajime,
（ｱﾅｳﾝｻｰ）
主に ライブ活動で
ご活躍中の一一 一(ひとつい はじめ)さんですが―
but this time it seems he might be playing the lead part.
この度
映画の主演をされるということです
I fell asleep...
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
寝ちまったか
（ｱﾅｳﾝｻｰ）
なんとハリウッド映画だそうですが
何か特別な…
Even with this thing, it takes all my effort to last 15 minutes in a fight...
チッ… 気ぃ抜きすぎだ クソバカ
こいつを着けてても
15分戦うのが精いっぱいだってのに
（はじめ）
日本人として適切に作用しています
彼はＥＶＥＮ(イーブン)を持っていませんか
そして ほかの人たちが
今日(こんにち) 日本人として―
非常に適切に 理解しましたか？
（はじめ）
言葉自体は
ネイティブな米国語を―
使わなくてはならないので…
（はじめ）
その他のしぐさや作法…
No one's home?
誰も いねえのか
まあいい　シャワーでも浴びるか
Fine with me.
Guess I'll take a shower.
ど… どうして前触れもなく
突発的に出現してるのって―
"Why would you just barge in without knocking?!"
ミサカはミサカは バスタオルに
手を伸ばすけど手遅れだったり
asks MISAKA asks MISAKA while frantically grasping for her bath towel.
なんで鍵かけねえんだよ？
Why didn't you lock the door?
Sorry about that.
（黄泉川）
悪い悪い
I'm used to living alone, so I totally forgot.
今まで１人暮らしだったから
忘れてたじゃんよ
Aiho, for now, cover yourself.
愛穂(あいほ) とりあえず巻いときなさい
"How can you stay so calm after being seen naked
like that?" ponders MISAKA ponders MISAKA.
２人とも
裸を見られて何ともないのって―
ミサカはミサカは
素朴な疑問を投げかけてみたり
Well, it's not like there's anything to get worked up over.
う～ん… 別に騒ぐほどのことでも
ないでしょう
This guy's still a kid, and we're adults.
この子は子供で
私らは大人じゃんよ
"Adults? More like old aunties," says MISA—
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
それは大人っていうより
おばはんっぽいかもって―
ミサカは… いたたた…
Ow ow ow!
"Don't knuckle burn my head like that!"
Be more careful next time, will you?
だから ちっとは
警戒しろっつってんだろうが
"...is what happpened," reports MISAKA reports MISAKA.
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
…ということがあったのって―
ミサカはミサカは
事後報告してみたり
"That information was already distributed
throughout the MISAKA Network."
（御坂10032）
それならば
既に ネットワークを介して―
配信されているので―
"Was there any particular reason to restate it orally?"
asks MISAKA as she calmly points the fact out.
わざわざ口頭で
言い直す必要もないのでは？
…と ミサカは冷静に指摘します
"I just wanted to say it out loud!" protests MISAKA protests MISAKA.
口頭で何度でも言いたいのって―
ミサカはミサカは
あの理不尽を許せずにいたり
"That said, you've managed to get yourself into quite
a ridiculous situation, trapped outside like this."
それで
マンションのオートロックの―
閉め出しを食らうとは
マヌケな状況ですね
"If MISAKA hadn't come by, you would have been stuck
out here alone,"
ミサカが通りかからなかったら―
あなたは ずっと
独りぼっちだったのでしょうか？
says MISAKA as she giggles quietly to herself.
…と ミサカは腹の中で
こっそり笑ってみせます
"It's not MISAKA's fault! It's that autolock!"
protests MISAKA protests MISAKA indignantly.
悪いのはミサカじゃなくて
オートロックなんだもんって―
ミサカはミサカは憤慨してみる
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
おい
あのクソガキは どこ行ったんだ？
Hey, where'd that little brat go?
Now that you mention it...
（芳川）
そういえば…
"You mean this?" asks MISAKA as she
attempts to confirm the strange question.
（御坂10032）
これですか？
…と ミサカは不意の質問に対して
確認作業を行います
"All the other MISAKA's have one, but MISAKA doesn't,"
states MISAKA states MISAKA glancing at it enviously.
ほかのミサカは
みんな それ持ってるのに―
ミサカだけは持ってないのって―
ミサカはミサカは
羨望のまなざしを送ってみたり
"This MISAKA is this MISAKA, and that MISAKA is that
MISAKA," says MISAKA as she advises MISAKA to give up.
あのミサカは あのミサカ
このミサカは このミサカです
…と ミサカは
暗に諦めろと告げてみます
もう…
ミサカも それ欲しいって―
"MISAKA wants that too!" whines MISAKA whines MISAKA trying to throw a tantrum like a spoiled child.
ミサカはミサカは
小さな外見を最大級に利用した―
ダダっ子交渉術を行使してみたり
"You may be trying to act cute, but that kind of behavior only annoys me," says MISAKA as she explains gently.
かわいらしいしぐさを
ねらっているのでしょうが―
同性は それを見ても
腹が立つだけなので逆効果です
…と ミサカは
懇切丁寧に解説します
ムゥ… あっ…
"Hey, 10032, could you bend over for a second?"
requests MISAKA requests MISAKA.
ねえ 10032号
ちょっと おじぎしてみてって―
ミサカはミサカは お願いしてみる
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
フフフッ… 隙ありって―
"Gotcha!" says MISAKA says MISAKA as her grab tactic succeeds!
ミサカはミサカは
強奪作戦に成功してみたり
"Try to get it back if you can!" taunts
MISAKA taunts MISAKA making her getaway.
や～い 悔しかったら
取り返してみろって―
ミサカはミサカは 勝利の余韻に
浸りながら猛ダッシュしていく！
"The time for a revolution has come," declares MISAKA-10032.
革命の時は来ました
…と 御坂10032号は
ここに宣言します
～♪
Next Episode
After Misaka Mikoto I have to deal with her little sister?
（上条）
御坂美琴の次は 御坂妹？
This time it's a tiny Misaka...
今度は ちっこい御坂まで
ちょ…
こんな所で暴れるんじゃねえ！
Wait, don't go rampaging here!
Index, that person with you...
…て インデックス
お前が一緒にいたヤツって…
Next time: "Serial Number."
次回 「検体番号(シリアルナンバー)」
When science and magic cross paths, this epic will begin!
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる